RESUME

Farukh Ahmed

Present Address: 357, Goyaltek Prodhan Sorok, Dokkinkhan, Dhaka-1230. Permanent Address: Vill: Montala, PS+PO: Kalmakanda, Dist: Netrokona.

Mobile No: 01932-821108, 01617-846669 Email: farukhahmed32joy@gmail.com

Career Summary:

I have been working diligently at NGOs for the last 6 years. I work with responsibilities, I have worked on a variety of projects, from which I am aware of all kinds of work, and my work experience is constantly increasing. I do project implementation, reports, collect data, I do provide skilled training, and does all the accounting work.

Professional Experience:-

1. Name of the Organization: READI- Research Evaluation And Development Initiative.

Name of the Project: BRAC Education Programme, Out of School Children Education Programme, Under (BNFE-Bureau of Non-Formal Education).

Programme Supervisor: - 03 July, 2022 to till now.

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Data Collection screening and admission process of Students. Establish Learners Center.
- Constitution of CMC (Central Management Committee) .
- Quarterly Parents/guardians Meeting.
- Monthly Teacher Coordination Meeting.
- School counseling session is conducted. Supervision and Monitoring of Teachers.
- See how students are being taught and brief teachers on how to teach better.
- Relations build up with Teacher, Parents/guardians and local govt.
- Monitoring & Reporting Weekly, Bi-Weekly, Monthly & Quarterly.
- Assists / supports the administrative activities and Training/Workshops/Events.

Additional work:

- Prepare Bill & Voucher (Debit, Credit & Journal), Bank Reconciliation, Advance register, Cheque register, Asset register etc maintain.
- Record and post all transactions in the cash book. Prepare and Maintain Cash book, Ledger book & Stock book. Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Half Yearly and Annual Financial Report.
- Accounts related others work.
- 2. Name of the Organization: READI- Research Evaluation And Development Initiative.

Name of the Project: Nutrition Security for Vulnerable Workers Project.

Name of Donor: GAIN-Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition.

Food Monitor-Cum-Accountant: - Duration- 18 August 2020 to 02 July 2022

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Factory Search & Selection.
- Maintain communication with all concerned factory, vendor.



- Monitor whether eating is healthy.
- To Monitor Whether food is being served in compliance with Corona and other hygiene rules.
- To ensure that food is distributed evenly among the workers.
- Fill in the report format monitoring the demand and supplier food.
- Prepare Bill & Voucher (Debit, Credit & Journal), Bank Reconciliation, Advance register, Cheque register, Asset register etc maintain.
- Record and post all transactions in the cash book.
- Prepare and Maintain Cash book, Ledger book & Stock book.
- Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Half Yearly and Annual Financial Report.
- Assists / supports the procurement process, administrative activities and Training/Workshops/Events
- 3. Name of the Organization: READI- Research Evaluation And Development Initiative.

Name of the Project: Vulnerable Group Development (VGD) Project, Directorate of Women Affairs at Trishal, Mymensingh.

Training Officer: - Duration- 1 October 2019 to 31 December 2020

Duties/Responsibilities:

- I am serving as instructor of Training (IGA training & Life Skills Development Training, 1000 women in 3 Unions).
- Collaborate to open a VGD account.
- To co-operate with VGD beneficiaries in making savings deposits.
- To provide life skills and income generating training to VGD beneficiaries etc.
- 4. Name of the Organization: READI- Research Evaluation And Development Initiative.

Name of the Project: (Social awareness campaign on fortified Oil and Salt at grass root level in the central regions of Bangladesh. Trinamul Pusti Ovijan Project) at Haluaghat & Dhubaura in Mymensingh. Indigenous Garo Communities.

Name of Donor: GAIN-Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition.

Accountant: - Duration- 02 July 2018 to 31 March 2019

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Prepare Bill & Voucher (Debit, Credit & Journal), Bank Reconciliation, Cash book, Ledger book,
 Stock book, Advance register, Cheque register, Asset register etc maintain.
- Record and post all transactions in the cash book.
- Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Half Yearly and Annual Financial Report.
- Perform others work related to accounts.
- Assists / supports the procurement process, administrative activities and Training/Workshops/Events.

Additional Work:

- Local nutrition club fill up formatting. Establish pusti Center.
- Attend Monthly meeting with beneficiaries about awareness build up on taking iodine salt and vitamin A.
- Coordination Meeting with Stakeholder. School counseling session is conducted.
- Relations build up with stakeholder like businessmen, bakery owner, hotel owner, and local govt.
- Baseline & End line Survey etc.

5. Name of the Organization: DJTI- Decent Job And Training Institute is a Concern of READI

Name of the Project Name: SHAMERTO (Sustainable Skills and Employment in Small Scale Agro

Food Processing Project) at Mymensingh.

Name of Donor: HELVETAS Swiss Intercooperation.

Accountant: - Duration- 02 July 2018 to 30 September 2019.

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Prepare Bill & Voucher (Debit, Credit & Journal), Bank Reconciliation, Cash book, Ledger book, Stock book, Advance register, Cheque register, Asset register etc maintain.
- Record and post all transactions in the cash book.
- Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Half Yearly and Annual Financial Report.
- Perform others work related to accounts.
- Assists / supports the procurement process, administrative activities and Training/Workshops/Events

Additional Work:

- All batch Data Entry & Web Entry.
- Providing short-term and long-term training to bakery staff to enhance their basic knowledge.
- Contact with job providing organization for bakery staff so that they can get a good service.
- Coordination with Consortium Members & others Organizations.
- Liaise with Food & Beverage Companies for Trainee Job placement.
- **6. Name of the Organization:** DJTI- Decent Job And Training Institute

Name of the Project Name: (Sudokkho Project-Skills training and employment: SMO & GFP) at Zirani bazar, Gazipur, Dhaka.

Name of Donor: Palladium International through DFID and SDC.

Accountant: - Duration-01 February 2018 to 30 June 2018.

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Participants Collection. All batch Data Entry & Web Entry.
- I am serving as instructor of Training. To do all the work of accounting.
- To do Contact with different company for participants job placement
- Purchase of goods for office & training. Other functions of the office etc.
- Prepare Bill & Voucher (Debit, Credit & Journal), Bank Reconciliation, Cash book, Ledger book, Stock book, Advance register, Cheque register, Asset register etc maintain.
- Record and post all transactions in the cash book. Accounts related others works.
- Prepare Monthly, Quarterly, Half Yearly and Annual Financial Report.
- Assists / supports the procurement process, administrative activities and Training/Workshops/Events

Others Experience:- Baseline & End line Survey, Feasibility Study, Impect Study, FGD, KII, Data Collection & Entry etc.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION:-

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

Institute Name : Kalmakanda Degree College.

Group : Business Studies

GPA : 4.30
Passing Year : 2014
Board : Dhaka

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Institute Name : Kalmakanda Pilot High School.

Group : Business Studies

GPA : 4.06 Passing Year : 2012 Board : Dhaka

Training

• Baking Level-1 (Sustainable Skills and Employment in Small Scale Agro Food Processing Project).

- Food Preparation Level-2 (Sustainable Skills and Employment in Small Scale Agro Food Processing Project).
- Foundation Training facilitated by BRAC.
- Subject Based Training facilitated by BRAC.
- Computer training Course.

Language Skills

- Bangla: Fluent in Speaking, reading & writing in Bengali (Mother Language)
- English: Fluent reading & writing and also have speaking ability as much as need.

Computer Literacy:

 Application Software: Compatible with Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Power Point, Internet etc.

Personal Information:

Father :Abdul Motalib.

Mother : Bedena Begum.

Date of Birth : 10-11-1995

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam
Sex : Male
Blood Group : O+

Marital status : Married. National ID : 7353947554

Height : 5' 11'' Weight : 75 kg

Reference:

1. Saifur Rahman 2. Manik Datta

Program Officer Upazila Program Manager

READI-Research Evaluation And BRAC.

Development Initiative BRAC Education Programme Phone: 01704-118118 Phone: 01719-530014

Email: saifur@readibd.org Email: manikdattabep@gmail.com

